My supervisor asked me to do a presentation next week
I want to start preparing for it now
but I don’t know what to do
It depends on what your goal is
Is the purpose of your presentation to inform
train or sell?
I think it’s to report on
the new sales campaign for our product
So my goal of this presentation is to keep everyone
updated on the progress of this campaign
Great
So do you know who will be at the presentation?
Who is your target audience?
You should analyze and understand your audience.
What are their work backgrounds,
age range and awareness of your topic?
I am speaking to a group of senior sales representatives
who are very experienced
and familiar with our product already
They are quite different from newbies
I don’t need to spend time explaining the product
or sales strategies to them, right?
Correct. Since you know your goal and your audience already
you can start setting the objectives for your presentation
What is the difference between a goal and an objective?
A goal is the general accomplishment
you aim to reach after the presentation
In your case, your goal is to let the participants
be aware of the recent sales campaign
Objectives are similar to goals but slightly different
Have you heard of a “SMART” objective?
Oh yes, it has become very popular
The S in SMART means specific
the M means measurable
the A is for attainable
R is for relevant and T means time-based
Right
Those are the five criteria a good objective should have
For example
what do you expect the audience to accomplish
after the presentation?
Set a deadline or a measure method
to evaluate their achievement
Let me try to set my objectives as follows
After this presentation, the audience should be able to
1. list three major activities of the campaign
2. talk about the good and the bad of these events so far
and 3. evaluate the effectiveness of this campaign
and give feedback by the end of this month
That sounds good
You now have very “smart” objectives for your presentation